rakbankdirect.ae 2017-09-15

# Privacy Policy - RAKBANK

The National Bank of Ras Al Khaimah (P.S.C.) (“RAKBANK”) is committed to providing the highest level of security and privacy regarding the collection and use of the customer’s personal information by the RAKBANK website. Personal information may be collected through the submission of service requests, online banking transactions or through the use of online financial tools such as interactive calculators. A detailed description of RAKBANK’s website privacy policy is provided below. If you have additional questions regarding the privacy and security of your personal information, please contact us on 04-2130000 or [_reportincident@rakbank.ae._](mailto:reportincident@rakbank.ae)

##  Respect of right to privacy 

RAKBANK maintains strict policies and security controls to ensure that customer information contained in the systems and files is protected. RAKBANK respects your right to privacy and takes every precaution to provide you with the same level of privacy within our bank that you receive through more traditional bank delivery channels. RAKBANK is committed to ensuring the privacy of its customers’ personal information.

##  Collection and use of personal information 

The collection of personal information online is designed to protect access to your accounts, to assist RAKBANK in providing you with the products and services you want and need. All personal information collected and stored by RAKBANK is used for specific business purposes to protect and administer your accounts and transactions, to comply with federal laws and banking regulations of the United Arab Emirates (“UAE”), and to help RAKBANK better understand your financial needs in order to design or improve our products and services. Employing stringent security measures in the collection of your personal information, all RAKBANK service requests are submitted to the secure administration site of RAKBANK. Once received by RAKBANK, only the bank’s approved personnel may open and process the application. Furthermore, auditing mechanisms have been put into place to further protect your information by identifying which employee(s) has accessed and in any way modified for example, updated or added to your personal information.

Unless restricted by applicable law, you agree that any and all personal information/data relating to you collected by RAKBANK from this website from time to time may be used and disclosed for such purposes and to such persons as may be authorised by RAKBANK. RAKBANK never requests its customers to disclose the account number, credit card information, user ID, Personal Identification Number (PIN) or any such information through e-mails. Any e-mail or written communication received by the customer, which appears to have been sent from RAKBANK seeking a customer’s personal and confidential information, should not be answered and RAKBANK should be advised.

##  Limited employee access to personal information 

RAKBANK limits its access to your personal information to only those employees who hold a business reason for having access to such information. RAKBANK also educates all their employees about the importance of confidentiality and customer privacy. In addition, individual usernames and passwords are used by approved RAKBANK personnel to access your personal information online, providing audit trails to further safeguard the privacy of your personal information.

##  Third-party disclosure restrictions 

RAKBANK follows strict privacy procedures in regard to protecting your personal information. In addition, RAKBANK requires all third parties with a business need to access this information to adhere to similar and equally stringent privacy policies. Personal information may be supplied to a third party in order to process customer transactions; if the customer requests it; the disclosure is required or allowed by law (i.e. exchange of information with reputable reporting agencies, subpoena, or the investigation of fraudulent activity, etc.); or in conjunction with joint marketing agreements we have entered into. RAKBANK does not provide account or personal information to other companies for the purpose of independent telemarketing or direct mail marketing of any non-financial products or services of those companies.

##  Online protection 

RAKBANK has taken all appropriate measures to protect the personal information provided by you to RAKBANK and uses several security levels.
